Gabriel Austin

linkedin.com/in/gabrielaustin • codebygabe.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Accomplished Web Development professional with a background of industrious, hands-on experience in developing and maintaining websites. Looking to apply master's level educational background, 3+ years of web development experience, and technical and non-technical communication skills to support effective web project execution across the software development life cycle.

CORE TECHNICAL SKILLS

Bootstrap framework, CSS3, Git, Google Analytics, HTML5, JavaScript, MySQL, Scrum, Search Engine Optimization (SEO), Trello

EXPERIENCE

Computer Science Teacher

Ascend Public Charter Schools, Brooklyn, NY

September 2022 — April 2023

- Spearheaded technical support meetings between internal tech staff and software vendor's tech staff to eliminate connection issues which led to 4 classes having consistent, unbreakable access to the applications needed for class
- Initiated conversations with local science, technology, engineering, arts, and mathematics (STEAM) teachers to brainstorm ways to make lessons more engaging which caused student participation to increase by nearly 50%
- Conducted lessons and practical classes for more than 200 students teaching them Scratch, HTML5, and CSS3 so they could have an active website portfolio

Web Developer

Fahrenheit Creative Group, Jackson, MS

October 2021 — July 2022

- Applied WordPress Content Management System, HTML5, and CSS3 aptitudes to generate efficient code by enhancing workload capacity that helped to expand business opportunities by 50%
- Translated meticulous user requirement analysis into user-friendly, attention-grabbing websites, decreasing bounce rate by 20% and increasing page views
- Transformed small businesses' websites through audit-informed techniques, improving site usability and enhancing user experience
- Established tailored documentation and training sessions to increase clients' website literacy and ensure seamless website management after deployment, increasing customer loyalty by 15%

Web Developer

AgSmarts, Memphis, TN

September 2015 — June 2016

- Exercised Ruby development skills to improve and maintain the user interface of the proprietary agricultural irrigation automation platform, reducing the Chief Technology Officer's workload
- Enhanced contracted, international web developer's capacity to accomplish project management and produce desired outcomes by implementing Scrum, Trello, and streamlining project timelines
- Achieved a highly efficient work arrangement for the contractor, saving AgSmarts \$1200 per month

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Management Information Systems

Graduated July 2017

University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, AL

Relevant coursework: Tech Based Project Management, Web Analytics, Tech Planning and Budgeting

Bachelor of Science, Computer Information Systems

Graduated July 2007

Alabama State University, Montgomery, AL